import type React from "react";
import { useState } from "react";
import { NavLink, useParams } from "react-router-dom";
import Answer from "../components/answer";

const questions = {
  gryffindor: [
    {
      question: "What is the Slytherin house animal?",
      choices: ["Badger", "Eagle", "Lion", "Snake"],
      correctAnswer: "Snake",
    },

    {
      question: "In which house is Harry Potter sorted at Hogwarts?",
      choices: ["Hufflepuff", "Slytherin", "Gryffindor", "Ravenclaw"],
      correctAnswer: "Gryffindor",
    },

    {
      question: "What main quality characterizes the members of Gryffindor?",
      choices: ["Loyalty", "Courage", "Intelligence", "Dumbledore"],
      correctAnswer: "Courage",
    },

    {
      question: "What is Gryffindor's symbol?",
      choices: [
        "Helga's Cup",
        "Godric's Sword",
        "Rowena's Diadem",
        "La mer Noire",
      ],
      correctAnswer: "Godric's Sword",
    },

    {
      question: "What is the Gryffindor house animal?",
      choices: ["Lion", "Eagle", "Badger", "Snake"],
      correctAnswer: "Lion",
    },
  ],

  hufflepuff: [
    {
      question:
        "Which potion allows someone to take the appearance of another person?",
      choices: [
        "Veritaserum",
        "Polyjuice Potion",
        "Felix Felicis",
        "Amortentia",
      ],
      correctAnswer: "Polyjuice Potion",
    },
    {
      question: "What is the name of Harryâ€™s famous owl?",
      choices: ["Scabbers", "Crookshanks", "Hedwig", "Buckbeak"],
      correctAnswer: "Hedwig",
    },

    {
      question: "Who is the Keeper of Keys and Grounds at Hogwarts?",
      choices: [
        "Argus Filch",
        "Rubeus Hagrid",
        "Albus Dumbledore",
        "Severus Snape",
      ],
      correctAnswer: "Rubeus Hagrid",
    },

    {
      question: "In which book do we learn about Horcruxes?",
      choices: [
        "The Goblet of Fire",
        "The Order of the Phoenix",
        "The Deathly Hallows",
        "The Half-Blood Prince",
      ],
      correctAnswer: "The Half-Blood Prince",
    },

    {
      question: "Which spell is used to kill someone instantly?",
      choices: ["Expelliarmus", "Avada Kedavra", "Lumos", "Petrificus Totalus"],
      correctAnswer: "Avada Kedavra",
    },
  ],

  ravenclaw: [
    {
      question: "Who is the head of Ravenclaw house?",
      choices: [
        "Professor Flitwick",
        "Professor Snape",
        "Professor McGonagall",
        "Professor Sprout",
      ],
      correctAnswer: "Professor Flitwick",
    },

    {
      question: "What is Voldemortâ€™s real name?",
      choices: [
        "Tom Marvolo Riddle",
        "Gellert Grindelwald",
        "Salazar Slytherin",
        "Severus Snape",
      ],
      correctAnswer: "Tom Marvolo Riddle",
    },

    {
      question: "What is the name of Neville Longbottomâ€™s mother?",
      choices: ["Lily", "Alice", "Molly", "Andromeda"],
      correctAnswer: "Alice",
    },

    {
      question:
        "What is the name of the magical law enforcement prison guarded by Dementors?",
      choices: ["Nurmengard", "Azkaban", "Gringotts", "St. Mungo's"],
      correctAnswer: "Azkaban",
    },

    {
      question: "What are the three objects that make up the Deathly Hallows?",
      choices: [
        "The Elder Wand, the Resurrection Stone, and the Invisibility Cloak",
        "The Philosopherâ€™s Stone, the Mirror of Erised, and the Sorting Hat",
        "The Basilisk Fang, the Marauderâ€™s Map, and the Goblet of Fire",
        "The Elder Wand, the Sword of Gryffindor, and the Firebolt",
      ],
      correctAnswer:
        "The Elder Wand, the Resurrection Stone, and the Invisibility Cloak",
    },
  ],
};

const Quiz: React.FC = () => {
  const { house } = useParams<{ house: string }>();
  const houseQuestions = questions[house as keyof typeof questions] || [];
  const [score, setScore] = useState(0);
  const [currentQuestionIndex, setCurrentQuestionIndex] = useState(0);
  const [showResult, setShowResult] = useState(false);

  const handleAnswerSelected = (answer: string) => {
    const currentQuestion = houseQuestions[currentQuestionIndex];
    if (answer === currentQuestion.correctAnswer) {
      setScore(score + 1);
    }
    const nextQuestionIndex = currentQuestionIndex + 1;
    if (nextQuestionIndex < houseQuestions.length) {
      setCurrentQuestionIndex(nextQuestionIndex);
    } else {
      setShowResult(true);
    }
  };

  return (
    <div className="quiz-container">
      <h1>Are you ready ? ðŸª„</h1>
      {showResult ? (
        <div className="result">
          <h2>
            Your Score: {score} / {houseQuestions.length}
          </h2>
          <NavLink to="/home" id="returnHome">
            <button type="button" className="returnHomeButton">
              Back home
            </button>
          </NavLink>
        </div>
      ) : (
        <Answer
          question={houseQuestions[currentQuestionIndex].question}
          choices={houseQuestions[currentQuestionIndex].choices}
          onAnswerSelected={handleAnswerSelected}
          answer={houseQuestions[currentQuestionIndex].correctAnswer}
        />
      )}
    </div>
  );
};

export default Quiz;
